<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ri:Resource xmlns:ri="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/RegistryInterface/v1.0" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:vr="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/VOResource/v1.0" xmlns:vs="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/VODataService/v1.0" xmlns:sn="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/SkyNode/v0.2" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:type="vs:CatalogService" created="2008-04-10T00:00:00" updated="2008-04-10T00:00:00" status="active">

  <title>The Hipparcos Main Catalogue</title>
  <shortName>HIPPARCOS</shortName>

  <identifier>ivo://jvo/vizier/I/239</identifier>

  <curation>
      <publisher>JVO</publisher>
      <creator>
         <name/>
      </creator>
      <contributor/>
      <contact>
         <name>Yuji SHIRASAKI</name>
      </contact>
  </curation>
  <content>
      <subject>Astrometry</subject>
      <subject>Photometry</subject>
      <subject>Catalogs</subject>
      <subject>Positions</subject>
      <subject>Stars</subject>
      <description>The Hipparcos and Tycho Catalogues are the primary products of the
    European Space Agency's astrometric mission, Hipparcos. The satellite,
    which operated for four years, returned high quality scientific data
    from November 1989 to March 1993.

    Each of the catalogues contains a large quantity of very high quality
    astrometric and photometric data. In addition there are associated
    annexes featuring variability and double/multiple star data, and solar
    system astrometric and photometric measurements. In the case of the
    Hipparcos Catalogue, the principal parts are provided in both printed
    and machine-readable form (on CDROM). In the case of the Tycho
    Catalogue, results are provided in machine-readable form only (on
    CDROM). Although in general only the final reduced and calibrated
    astrometric and photometric data are provided, some auxiliary files
    containing results from intermediate stages of the data processing, of
    relevance for the more-specialised user, have also been retained for
    publication. (Some, but not all, data files are available from the
    Centre de Donnees astronomiques de Strasbourg.)

    The global data analysis tasks, proceeding from nearly 1000 Gbit of
    raw satellite data to the final catalogues, was a lengthy and complex
    process, and was undertaken by the NDAC and FAST Consortia, together
    responsible for the production of the Hipparcos Catalogue, and the
    Tycho Consortium, responsible for the production of the Tycho
    Catalogue. A fourth scientific consortium, the INCA Consortium, was
    responsible for the construction of the Hipparcos observing programme,
    compiling the best-available data for the selected stars before launch
    into the Hipparcos Input Catalogue. The production of the Hipparcos
    and Tycho Catalogues marks the formal end of the involvement in the
    mission by the European Space Agency and the four scientific
    consortia.

    For more complete and detailed information on the data, the user is
    advised to refer to Volume 1 ("Introduction and Guide to the Data",
    ESA SP-1200) of the printed Hipparcos and Tycho Catalogues. The user
    should also note that in order to convert the Double and Multiple
    Systems (Component solutions) data file hipdmc.dat into FITS format
    it is first necessary to filter the file according to whether the
    entry is a component record (identified by COMP in field DCM5) or a
    correlation record (identified by CORR in field DCM5) because of the
    different structures of the respective records. On a Unix system this
    can be achieved as follows:

    grep COMP hipdmc.dat &gt; hdmcom.dat
    grep CORR hipdmc.dat &gt; hdmcor.dat

    The catalogue description file (this file) gives the relevant
    information for converting the main data files, including hdmcor.dat
    and hdmcom.dat, into FITS format.

    The machine readable data files (i.e. those available on CD-ROM and
    the subset available from the CDS) contain several extra fields in
    addition to the data from the printed catalogue. These fields are
    identified by the letter `M' in the data label (e.g. the field DGM1
    contains data only available in the machine readable file
    hipdmg.dat).</description>
      <source>http://vizier.nao.ac.jp/viz-bin/Cat?I/239</source>
      <referenceURL>http://vizier.nao.ac.jp/viz-bin/Cat?I/239</referenceURL>
      <type>Catalog</type>
      <contentLevel>Research</contentLevel>
  </content>

  <capability standardID="ivo://ivoa.net/std/OpenSkyNode" xsi:type="vr:Capability">
      <interface version="1.0" role="std" xsi:type="vr:WebService">
         <accessURL>http://jvo.nao.ac.jp/skynode/services/SkyNodeForHIP</accessURL>
      </interface>
  </capability>

  <coverage>
      <waveband>Optical</waveband>
  </coverage>
</ri:Resource>