<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ri:Resource xmlns:ri="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/RegistryInterface/v1.0" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:vr="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/VOResource/v1.0" xmlns:vs="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/VODataService/v1.0" xmlns:sn="http://www.ivoa.net/xml/SkyNode/v0.2" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:type="vs:CatalogService" created="2008-04-10T00:00:00" updated="2008-04-10T00:00:00" status="active">

  <title>UBV photometry and proper motions in M13 (Kadla, 1966)</title>
  <shortName>Kadla1966</shortName>
  <identifier>ivo://jvo/vizier/II/248</identifier>
  <curation>
      <publisher>JVO</publisher>
      <creator>
         <name>Kadla Z.I.</name>
      </creator>
      <contributor/>
      <contact>
         <name>Yuji SHIRASAKI</name>
      </contact>
  </curation>
  <content>
      <subject>Globular Clusters</subject>
      <subject>Photometry</subject>
      <subject>Proper motions</subject>
      <description>    The first epoch plates of 8 globular clusters, available in the plate
    collection of the Pulkovo Observatory, were taken with the normal
    astrograph at the end of the last and beginning of this century. These
    plates had been measured previously by N. Gamalei [1948, IzPul, 141]
    in order to determine the proper motions of the clusters. From 40 to
    62 stars were used for this purpose and these were assumed to be
    cluster members on the basis of their proximity to the cluster
    centers. The epoch differences ranged from 30 to 45 years. As this
    time interval has now increased considerably (by about a factor of
    two), it is planned to redetermine the proper motions of these
    clusters, using more precise criteria for the selection of stars
    belonging to the cluster. In the previous study (N. Gamalei [1948,
    IzPul, 141]) only a limited number of field reference stars were
    measured, and as more complete data on the cluster, cluster members
    and field stars is desirable all the star images on the plates in an
    area 80'x80' will be measured in the present program. For future
    studies of the orbits of galactic clusters it is important that the
    absolute proper motions be on one system and therefore special
    attention should be devoted to this problem.

    The present paper is a continuation of an investigation of M13 and
    deals with the determination of the proper motions and U, B, V
    magnitudes of separate stars and also a redetermination of the proper
    motions of the cluster.

    The U, B, V magnitudes of the majority of 923 stars with measured
    proper motions were found from plates (table 2) taken with the 2 meter
    Schmidt telescope at Tautenburg and kindly lent to us by Professor N.
    Richter. The photoelectric standards as given by Savedoff
    [1956AJ.....61..254S] (table 7) and also U B V magnitudes of six
    bright field stars (table 8) observed by Mayer were used for
    calibration. A comparison of the determined B and V magnitudes of
    stars within an area of about 10'x10' centered on the cluster with
    those obtained by other authors indicates that the probable external
    errors do not exceed +/-0.03mag (table 15). However as the
    photoelectric magnitudes of fainter field stars were not available, a
    slight systematic error may be present in the derived magnitudes of
    these stars.

    Data on the plates used for the determination of the proper motions
    were given in Kadla [1963AZh....40..691K]. The relative proper motion
    of M 13, redetermined on the basis of a larger number of cluster
    members (80 in all, measured on 4 pairs of plates with a mean epoch
    difference equal to 61.4 years) is found to be {mu}x=+0.0008",
    {mu}y=-0.0014" with a probable error of +/-0.0002".
</description>
      <source>Izv. Glav. Astron. Obs. 181, 93 (1966)</source>
      <referenceURL>http://vizier.nao.ac.jp/viz-bin/Cat?II/248</referenceURL>
      <type>Catalog</type>
      <contentLevel>Research</contentLevel>
  </content>

  <capability standardID="ivo://ivoa.net/std/OpenSkyNode" xsi:type="vr:Capability">
      <interface version="1.0" role="std" xsi:type="vr:WebService">
         <accessURL>http://jvo.nao.ac.jp/skynode/services/SkyNodeForII248</accessURL>
      </interface>
  </capability>

  <coverage>
      <waveband>Optical</waveband>
  </coverage>
</ri:Resource>